briscoes.co.nz 2017-06-25

# Privacy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for Briscoe Group (including the Briscoes website at [www.briscoes.co.nz](http://www.briscoes.co.nz/)) and covers what we gather, how we look after it, use it, and how to correct or change it.

**Privacy Commitment**

Briscoe Group values our customers and respects their privacy.  We recognise the trust you place in us through your dealings with us.  We do everything we can to maintain that trust.  Under law, your rights to privacy are also protected.  Privacy laws place strict requirements on us to treat certain information collected as confidential, to store information securely and to allow you easy access to check and correct your information.

**Scope of our Privacy policy**

Our Privacy Policy applies to the personal information we collect, maintain, store and use about you as our customers, visitors to our website and other digital services, job applicants and members of the public.  Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the brands owned by us, including Briscoes, Rebel Sport and Living and Giving. 

**Collection**

Briscoe Group may collect personal information about you when you create an account, contact us, enter a competition, make a purchase either online or instore, or join a mailing list.  The types of personal information we may collect includes your name, contact details, date of birth, gender, company name (if applicable), and enquiry or complaint details.  We may require this information to be able to provide you with goods or services.

We also collect personal information through our records of your transactions and interactions (including by email, phone, and online) with Briscoe Group.  In some cases personal information may be collected from our related companies, your representatives and public sources. 

If you are a candidate for employment, we may collect other information as further set out in our application forms or during the recruitment process.  This may include information relating to your employment history, working eligibility rights, suitability for the role you are applying for, and your referee details.

**Use**

We collect and use your personal information to provide, administer, improve and personalise your experience with Briscoe Group and our products and services, to run competitions, conduct surveys, process payments and refunds, maintain and update our records, or verify your identity.  We may not be able to do these things without your personal information, such as deliver your online orders or respond to your enquiries. 

We do not sell or rent your information to third parties, however we do use other companies and individuals to assist us with payment, point of sale, marketing, data processing, IT, archival, auditing, accounting, customer contact, legal, business consulting, banking, delivery, data analysis, document management, research, investigation, insurance, website and other services. These companies are not authorised to use your personal information for any other purposes.

If you are a candidate for employment, we collect information to assess your suitability for a position within our business and for other purposes such as contacting referees, and performing background checks.

**Promotional communications**

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us.  If you prefer not to receive our promotional information from us, please let us know by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our communications, or by clicking into your account.

**Online Security**

Briscoe Group utilises a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information.  All user contact information is contained behind a firewall and only accessible by a limited number of employees who have special access rights.  As an added safeguard, Briscoe Group does not store credit card information.

We take website and credit card security extremely seriously and always endeavour to provide a secure, safe platform from which to conduct online transactions.  We use the industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts information as it is transmitted over the internet.  This encryption scrambles details such as credit card numbers and personal information, so that other computers are unable to decipher the information, ensuring privacy and security. 

However, please note that whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard the personal data that you provide to us, no transmission over the Internet can ever be guaranteed secure.  Consequently, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data that you transfer over the internet to us.

If you are using a computer or terminal in a public location, we recommend that you always log out and close the website browser when you complete an online session for your security.  In addition, we recommend that you take the following security measures to enhance your online safety:

  1.      Keep your account passwords private.  Remember, anybody who knows your password may access your account.
  2.      When creating a password, use at least 8 characters.  A combination of letters and numbers is best.  We also recommend that you frequently change your password.  You can do this by going to ‘My Account’ and clicking ‘Change your password’.

**Personal information access**

We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that personal information held by us is accurate and up-to-date. You are entitled to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not we hold personal information about you and you are entitled to reasonable access to this information. You may also request:

1.             That we correct this information if it is inaccurate; and

2.             That your details do not appear on our database.

You can make changes to your personal information on the "My Account" page, by contacting us using the "Contact Us" page on this site, or by calling our free phone number - 0800 274 726.

**General**

By using our websites, you are consenting to the collection of information by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  Please note that we reserve our right to amend, remove, or vary this policy without notice.  You should check this page regularly to take notice of any changes we have made to this policy.

**Cookies**

Our website uses “cookies”, which are small data files that are stored on your computer when you visit a website.  Cookies enable you to shop on our websites and may be used in a variety of ways to enhance or personalise your online browsing and shopping experience.

To make full use of the online shopping features of the Briscoe Group websites, your computer, tablet or mobile phone will need to accept cookies, as we can only provide you with certain features of the website by using them.  If cookies are switched off, you may not be able to make a purchase on the Briscoe Group websites.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions relating to Privacy, or to the Briscoe Group Privacy Policy, please contact us.
